The last race of the Classics, the Kikuka Sho,
is just around the corner!
The final showdown between these
three rivals has us on the edge of our seats!
The Kikuka Sho is a 3,000 meter endurance race
and will be the first of the sort for all of our contestants.
First up, we have T.M. Opera O—
The grand finale!
On a stage worthy of its name as the final of the Triple Crown,
the last title shall be mine!
All shall swoon at the sight of my running—a run fit for an Overlord that will not disappoint my rivals!
W-We're certainly looking forward to it.
Next up, we have Narita Top Road!
Y-Yes.
You were overtaken by Admire Vega
at both the Derby and the GII race the other day.
How do you feel?
And what are your thoughts on the upcoming Kikuka Sho?
Ayabe-san is really strong.
Honestly, losing to her is frustrating.
But that's what also motivates
me to improve myself,
so that I can win next time.
Let's both give it our best
at the Kikuka Sho, Ayabe-san!
I'm not going to lose.
It doesn't matter which race it is
or who I'm racing against.
I'm going to win.
Hashiridashita hitomi ga
Eyes that being to run,
mezasuno wa ichiban shika nai
aspiring to nothing more than number one
Glorious one moment
shouri de shika tsukamenai kiseki
a miracle that can only achieve victory
Umamusume: Pretty Derby
Road to the Top
Onaji toki wo irodotte
Coloring the very moment,
kagayaki tachi ga jibun wo miteru kara
because the bright lights are looking at me.
Genkai nante kimerarenai
I can't set limits,
unmei ga raibaru
destiny is my rival
Believe Dream
Akogare wa mou chousen ni nattanda
My longing has already become a challenge
Believe Pride
Butai ni tatsun da tte tsuyoi kanjou
I have a strong feeling that I'll be on the stage
Believe Yell
Kotaetai kimochi mo dakishime
Embracing the feeling of wanting to respond
Ima mirai e geeto ga hiraiteku
Now the door of the future opens,
reesu ga hajimatteku
the race begins
Issei taafu ni fuku kaze ni kawaru
It will become the wind blowing on the grass at once
mune no oku no atsui omoi wa
The passion in my heart,
dare ni mo yuzure wa shinai kara
I won't let anyone take it away from me.
Kakenuketeku sokudo wa
The speed at
watashi tachi no sakebi nanda
which we run is our cry
Kisoiau hodo ni hibiiteku
The more we race, the more it resonates
Running to the top!
Eikou to iu gooru e to mukau kiseki
The miracle of running towards the goal of glory
Episode 4: One Dream
Be careful, you're losing pace.
Right!
It's tough, but you can do this.
You're already getting stronger.
Okay!
The Kikuka Sho is a test of endurance.
You need enough stamina to get through the long distance...
As we know from the past few races,
she won't be able to win against Admire Vega.
It may be risky, but we have to set the pace ahead of time.
It'd be ideal if we could make it a battle of endurance with the long spurts.
It'll be different from what
we've been working on up until now,
but this will give us the best chance.
I need to prevent my opponents from doing what they do best—that's my strategy.
If I keep running the same way as I have before,
I won't be able to win against Ayabe-san or Opera O-san.
I know that...
I know that but...
I...
O-Opera O-san!
Your drink's been waiting ages for you, you know?
Behold the color of these clear skies.
Surely the day of the Kikuka Sho will be just like this.
The skies will be celebrating the grand occasion for us.
Right...
The spectators shall put their hands up,
shielding their eyes from
the rays of the autumn sun.
And from an even brighter
brilliance that will blind them!
That's right—me!
The moment I obtain the final crown,
the audience will be intoxicated and rejoice at the coming of a new era,
in which I shall reign as Overlord!
What's the matter?
Are you too dazzled by my brilliance?
I was just thinking how amazing it is that you're always so confident, Opera O-san.
Opera-san, don't you ever have times when you feel lost,
or frustrated at the limits of your own abilities?
Certainly not!
That is because I see the road of the Overlord stretching out endlessly before me.
I have no choice...
but to advance!
Do you not see the path that lies in front of you?
Top Road.
Trainer-san!
H-Hey. Something wrong?
I have a favor...
to ask regarding the Kikuka Sho.
This is my punishment...
for taking the very races you loved from you.
It's okay.
I'll keep running until the end.
I can't believe that the last thing
I'm offering up to you with my running...
will be...
the Kikuka crown.
Ayabe-san!
I have something I'd like to tell you, Ayabe-san!
It's something I have to let you know now!
What is it?
The Kikuka Sho is our last chance for the Classics...
and... I'm going to win against you!
Up until now,
I've lost again and again and cried out of frustration.
I've always looked up to you, Ayabe-san.
I wanted to catch up to you so badly.
Ayabe-san, you said it didn't matter
who you were running against.
But for me...
You are my goal and my rival, Ayabe-san!
And that's why I'm going to run
at the Kikusho Sho and win it my way!
I'm definitely going to beat you!
Stop it!
You're...
too bright...
Whenever you get close,
I... start losing sight of the stars...
I can't afford... to make any more mistakes!
So stop being so friendly to me.
I... want to run with you!
It's fun running together with you, Ayabe-san!
I've watched the footage from the Derby over and over again.
At first, I was scared to even look at what happened.
Even though I ran my best,
I still couldn't win against you, Ayabe-san.
But you really are amazing at running, Ayabe-san.
Your run is so strong and beautiful—
as if you're enjoying it so, so much!
I thought to myself,
I want to run like that too.
Together with you from here on.
I...
want to be your biggest rival, Ayabe-san.
I... don't need... any of that.
Then, I'll show you at the Kikuka Sho that you do.
Once again we find ourselves beneath the autumn skies,
ready for another season of the Kikuka Sho.
Which runner will make their way first through
the uncharted territory of a 3000-meter endurance race
to claim the final crown?
Well...
This is where my guidance ends.
The rest is up to you.
Anything you're unsure about?
No, I'm all right.
Good.
Run it your way, with everything you've got!
Okay!
I'm off!
You want to find your own way?
It's a once-in-a-lifetime race.
I want to be able to believe in myself until the end.
You and everyone else cheered me on and told me how much you liked my running.
Now I want to believe in myself too
and keep on racing.
The victory everyone's hoping for... I want to run and bring it to reality.
I want to let everyone know that this is how Narita Top Road runs.
That's it.
You may be clumsy at times,
but you're always full of determination—
and that's why I became your trainer.
O-Opera O-san!
Relax, relax!
Wouldn't want you coming to me after, saying you couldn't run like you always do
because you were so nervous.
Whether you laugh or cry, this is the last race!
The victor shall be none other than myself!
No.
This time...
I'm going to win!
I'll win this.
The crowds are going wild as the runners enter the gate for the Kikuka Sho!
Our runners are all lined up.
Ready to embark on the road to the top!
And they're off!
All fifteen runners are off to a beautiful start and heading toward the third turn.
Admire Vega is keeping her place midfield.
Close by we have T.M. Opera O,
and Narita Top Road on the inside.
You can do it, Top Road!
Let's go, Prez!
Show 'em what you've got, Top Road!
Her pace is... rather slow.
They're rounding the fourth turn and passing by the main stands on their first lap.
Narita Top Road is in third place, keeping close to the inside.
I have to wait for the right timing! I won't miss it!
Behind her is T.M. Opera O.
Admire Vega is running on the outside—
the two are neck and neck.
This is nothing...
compared to the pain my sister feels...
from not being able to run...
They're off the first homestretch and moving on to the first turn, settling for a slower pace.
I know she's savin' energy, but this is pretty slack...
Top Road should be going for it soon.
If she doesn't gain some distance between her and the others while it's still early in the race,
it'll be the Derby all over again.
Narita Top Road is glancing over at the outside!
Is she checking the positions of her rivals?
But she doesn't move yet.
The runners are going at a moderate pace,
rounding the second turn and onto the next stretch.
It's almost excruciating watching
how slowly the race is unfolding...
When will you make your move, Top Road-san?
And Ayabe-san.
They're about to tackle a critical part of
the Kyoto course—the elevated third turn.
The audience is ecstatic as the fifteen runners make their way up the hill.
They'll make a dash for it after clearing the hill!
Is she still gonna make it in time?
Of course she is!
Top Road won't let us down!
Is it going to be okay?
Top Road-senpai...
Once someone starts speeding up,
they're all going to pick up the pace.
Just when will Top Road break out into a spurt?
Admire Vega and T.M. Opera O are also keeping their paces moderate, with only 800 meters left!
It's not the end. It can't be the end yet!
Admire Vega emerges to the front!
T.M. Opera O follows!
But the other runners are too congregated, preventing T.M. Opera O from reaching the front!
They're entering the fourth turn once again.
Ayabe-san...
Go, Top Road!
I still... I still have a chance.
A chance to show them how I run!
A chance to live up to everyone's hopes!
They've rounded the fourth turn and are moving on to the final stretch!
Top Road-san!
Top Road!
Prez!
Top Road-senpai!
Narita Top Road is making her move!
She runs past the rest and reaches the front in a single dash!
Narita Top Road takes her position at the front!
Rapid Builder picks up the pace!
From the edge, T.M. Opera O is closing in fast.
Admire Vega falls back to fourth, fifth position. Narita Top Road is taking the lead!
I can't lose...
I want to catch up...
But why... why...
It's the last one...
But I want to... keep... running!
Hmm.
That's right.
It's fun...
running with those two, isn't it?
You...
I feel the same!
I had a lot of fun!
So keep your eyes on what's in front, Onee-chan.
Don't look back, and just run!
Wait...
Wait.
I'll bear the fate for both of us.
From now on, you should have as much fun as you want racing!
Onee-chan.
I'm sorry...
I...
It's fun running together with you, Ayabe-san!
I want to run like that too.
I want to be your biggest rival, Ayabe-san!
Narita Top Road is at the front! At last,
Narita Top Road is taking the initiative!
Narita Top Road is ascending the road to the top!
From the outside we have
Rapid Builder and T.M. Opera O!
T.M. Opera O is making a dash!
Will she catch up to Narita Top Road?
Having lost to her rivals at
the Satsuki Sho and the Derby,
the Classics have not been easy
for Narita Top Road!
Will Narita Top Road finally be able to attain her dream at the very end?
Rapid Builder and T.M. Opera O are hot on her heels, also aiming for the crown!
Who will it be to reach
the end of the Classic Road first?
Top Road! You can do it!
We're with you!
Top Road!
Run...
Run and climb...
the road to the top!
This is me...
Will Narita Top Road reach the finish line first?
Or will T.M. Opera O eclipse her?
Narita Top Road! It's Narita Top Road at the front!
This is the road everyone knew I could run...
Narita Top Road clears the finish!
Victory goes to Narita Top Road!
Top Road has finally done it!
Crowns have slipped through her fingers again and again.
But Narita Top Road refused to give up
and continued pushing her way to the top!
She's raising her arm in victory! Look how happy she is!
Top Road's done it!
Her trainer looks extremely pleased!
That was a run befitting the front lines of the Classics indeed.
Finally...
I've finally won...
I suffered defeat again and again...
But... I didn't want to give up.
I... From the bottom of... my heart...
Thank you, everyone!
Thank you.
I'll work harder from here on.
So just watch.
That was perfect.
Opera O-san...
Someday, I'll also...
Huh?
Don't worry, Doto.
There's still a lot more.
Eehhhhhh! That's too many!
Ayabe-san! Opera O-san!
Hey, wait...
The perfect shot for...
today's Umagram!
Encore! Encore! Encore! Encore! Encore!
Josotsuke kitai o koete yukou (Winding days)
Let's run up and go beyond our dreams! (Winding days!)
Jibun rashii bukiyo na hitamukisade
Every time the legend grows more beautiful
Densetsu ga utsukushia masutabi (My best days)
With your own clumsy dedication! (My best days!)
Sekaiju hakushukassai hibiiteku uta
The opera resounds with applause all over the world!
Kizu o dakuhi mo shirube no yoni
Even on the days when I hold my wounds,
Kirameku omoi munearukara
I'm sure I'll become a star
kitto hoshi ni nareru
because I have feelings that sparkly like guidance
Hashiri tsuzukeyo
Let's keep running!
Donna mirai demo chikau kara
I swear no matter what the future holds!
Akiramenai ha-to
I won't give up.
Miteite hoshii...
I want you...
kirari matataku
to see shimmer.
Kimi to tsukutteku Starry heavens
I will make a starry heavens with you!
Itsukano yume ga kyo no sora e
Someday's dream to today's sky!